ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
煮粥达人
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
滚成一个团子
翻译
某茶晚安
showeryhe
翻译
潇湘月影
冬麟
时间轴
Kallen   今
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第二季
第七集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
这不等于判了死刑
This is not a death sentence.
我没事
I'm okay.
这只是个麻烦而已
This is a complication, that's it.
天晓得我们克服过不少麻烦了  对吗
Lord knows we've overcome our fair share of those, right?
我可以  辞职
I can... I can leave work.
我可以辞职待在家里照顾你
I can quit and stay and make sure you're all right.
唐娜  这不能也不会改变任何事
Donna, this cannot, will not derail anything.
你的工作  你在做的一切
Your work... everything that you're doing.
那会让我心碎的  我感觉很好
That would break my heart. I feel fine.
是的  我的手有点无力
Yes, my hands are a little weak,
还有些小问题  有些小毛病
and, yes, there are small things, tiny things here and there,
但是我感觉很好
but I feel good, okay?
我要好好生活
I'm gonna live my life.
我要推进开办公司的计划
I'm moving forward with the company.
戈登  怎样做啊
Gordon, how?
我的办公室离床就23步远
My office is 23 steps from the bedroom.
不用开车  不用通勤
There's no driving, no commute,
我的工程师都是我最信任的朋友
my engineers are my most trusted friends.
即使发生最糟的情况  我还有你
And worst-case scenario, you're here.
我们会没事的  好吗
We're gonna be okay, okay?
我很抱歉你觉得你不能告诉我
I'm sorry you felt like you couldn't tell me.
我太害怕了  我拿不准
I was... I was scared. I didn't know.
我现在在了  好吗  我在了
I'm here now, okay? I'm here.
等等  别  我们能不能...
Wait, wait. No, it's okay. Um, can we just, uh...
好  好
Yeah. Yeah.
我们就...
Let's just...
你觉得一万平方英尺的办公区怎么样
What do you think about 10,000 square feet of office space?
免费提供  设在公司外
We'll do it gratis and off-site.
远离石油生意的恶臭
Nowhere near the stench of the oil business.
我想他们会喜欢的
I think they'll love it.
完全不必跟西装打交道
They'll never have to see a suit and tie.
你有穆特尼现地址的分区记录吗
Do you have the zoning records on Mutiny's current address?
我们只需要就地向外扩张
Just to take that further for a second,
他们现在的位置  东边的社区不是很太平
where they are now, east side, neighborhood's a little rough,
而且那些房子
house itself hasn't seen a
自A型车发明后就没再刷过漆了
coat of paint since the invention of the Model A,
福特公司1928年推出车
但是公司的核心竞争力就埋在墙里呢
but the heart of the company is sewn up into its walls.
我们可以吸纳这种个性化  省点钱
We could save some coin and embrace that motley spirit.
我们完全可以
There's nothing stopping us from
买下他们的房子  和整个街区
buying up the house, the entire block.
把那里变成个迷你园区
We could turn the place into a mini campus.
让他们设计  按他们的心意去开发
Let them design it, grow it as they see fit.
尽可能少做改变
Change as little as possible.
然后他们可以在那里
Then they could pepper the place
摆上桌上足球和游戏机
with foosball tables and arcade cabinets.
肯定比我们的养老金计划
That would certainly win more votes
和牙医医保更能吸引他们
than our 401 and platinum dental.
再加上一批IBM 4361超级迷你机
Drop in a grid of IBM 4361 Superminis,
300条专用电话线
300 dedicated phone lines,
直接访问主机的管理员权限
give them direct admin access to the mainframe,
我想就足以搞定他们了
I think we got 'em.
太棒了
That's brilliant.
干得好  乔
Great work, Joe.
给他们打个电话  我们把这事谈妥
Give 'em a call. Let's get this thing done.
赌三块和我的毁灭博士  选红色
Three bucks and my Doctor Doom says red all the way.
漫威漫画中神奇四侠的宿敌
我赌康  选蓝色
I'll bet Kang on blue.
漫威漫画中未来世界银河系的统治者
康  伙计  人人都有康
Kang? Dude, everyone has Kang.
我有5个康  阿基有11个康
I have five Kangs. Arki has 11 Kangs.
康就是手办里的大众脸
Kang is like the John Q. Public of action figures.
好吧  赌我的黑色蜘蛛侠
Fine, my black Spider-Man.
好耶
Yeah!
一  二  三
One, two, three.
各位  为什么没人在工作
Guys! Whoa, why is no one working?
-网络出问题了吗  -还没
- Is something wrong with the network? - Not yet.
除非乔·麦克米伦早饭吃得不爽了
Unless Joe MacMillan's morning coffee tastes bad.
好吧  你们安静点
Okay, well, shh.
实在是不好意思
Hi, sorry about that.
没关系的  我养大了三个闹腾小子
Oh, please, I raised three rambunctious boys.
这里就像在家一样
The place feels like home.
汤姆小时候什么样
What was Tom like as a kid?
-天啊  -我尽量说点好听的
- Oh, God. - I'll try not to embarrass him too much.
你仅仅十分钟前
Oh, you say that 10 minutes after
还告诉她我在你床上尿床的事呢
telling her about the time that I wet your bed.
但是汤米小时候可乖了
But little Tommy was the golden child,
和他的兄弟比起来他更喜欢待在家里
even if he was more of an indoor boy than his brothers.
每天放学
Every day after school,
我都给他纸杯蛋糕和番茄蛋黄酱  奖励他陪我
he got a cupcake and a Kayo just for keeping me company.
-挺受宠嘛  -可不是
- Oh, spoiled. - Always.
我该去赶车了
Oh, I gotta get to the depot.
好的
Yeah, okay.
好
Oh, yeah.
卡梅伦  多谢你招待午餐
Cameron, thank you so much for lunch.
见到你很高兴
It was great meeting you.
见到您也很高兴
No, it was great to meet you.
我很久没见过汤姆这么开心了
I haven't seen Tom this happy in a while.
多谢你给了他一个这么棒的机会
Thank you for giving him such a wonderful opportunity here.
有他我们也很荣幸
We're glad to have him.
这是一个非常  非常特别的地方
This is a very, very special place.
我相信你们会取得巨大成功的
And I know you're bound to have tremendous success.
多谢
Thanks.
-再见了  亲爱的  -家里见
- Bye, baby. - Okay, I'll see you at home.
-再见  -好了
- Bye. - All right. Okay.
今天吃奶酪鸡扒可以吗
Um, chicken parmesan, is that okay?
他还会做饭呢
And he can cook, too.
-你比不了吧  -比不了
- Can you beat that? - No.
好了
Okay.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
小汤米
Little Tommy.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我知道她有点咄咄逼人
I know she can be intense.
见到她我很高兴
I liked meeting her.
穆特尼
Mutiny.
-卡梅伦  我是乔  -是谁
- Cameron, it's Joe. - Who is it?
西方集团要收购你们
Westgroup wants to buy you.
是他吗  他又要断我们的网了
Is it him? Is he cutting us off?
我明天就带着正式收购协议过去
I'm coming over with an official acquisition offer tomorrow.
卡梅伦
Cameron?
卡梅伦  这是好消息
Cameron, this is good news.
我保证
I swear.
乔马上就要到了
Okay, Joe's gonna be here any minute.
我想先听他说完
So, I'm thinking that we'll listen to him, hear him out,
然后表现得专业点  委婉地拒绝他  好吧
and then act professional and then just let him down easy, right?
-我得请段时间的假  -现在吗
- I'm gonna need some time off. - Now?
今天会后开始  至少得几天
Starting after the meeting, a few days, at least.
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
就是
It's, uh--
可以谈了吗
We ready to talk?
老天爷
Jesus.
-就这样了吗  -不是
- So that's it, huh? - No.
这只是些数字
Those are just the numbers.
还有别的东西
Here are some others.
清单如下  31台康懋达64电脑
Inventory: 31 Commodore 64 machines,
每台配有1541型外置软驱
each with a 1541 peripheral floppy,
12块最新采购的
12 recently purchased
ST-412接口的10M备份硬盘
ST-412 10-meg hard drives for backup,
22名员工平均每月可用3000度电
22 employees burning on average 3,000 kilowatt hours per month,
1284个付费用户
1,284 paying subscribers,
以及一台用麦斯威尔滤网的咖啡机
and one coffee machine using Maxwell filters.
我的意思是  你不在意数字
My point is, you don't care about numbers.
你也不该在意
You shouldn't.
这地方的特别之处
What makes this place special is
是人们分享食谱  建议
people sharing recipes, advice,
生活经历  交流
human experiences, connection,
只需要一根电话线
over the speed of a phone line.
穆特尼的王牌不是游戏  而是人
Mutiny's killer app isn't games, it's people.
你如果和我们签约
And when you sign with us,
你就不需要担心数字了
you won't have to worry about numbers anymore.
而是让我们处理那部分
You can let us handle that part
这样你就能专注于你爱做的
so you can focus on what you love,
也就是将人们聚集到一起
which is bringing people together.
我们不想削减游戏开发
We're not interested in minimizing games.
我也不想
Neither am I.
游戏是这个公司的创新命脉
Games are the innovative lifeblood of this company.
对于技术突破至关重要
Vital for technological breakthrough.
对于带来新用户举足轻重
Essential for bringing users into the door.
但他们加入后
But once they've arrived,
交流就比游戏内容更重要了
connection trumps content.
从第一天起  西方集团将开始
Starting day one, Westgroup will begin
把你们的网络拓展到全球
a global expansion of your network.
也就是说可以触及无数
That means reaching thousands and thousands
遍布全球的独立用户
of isolated users all over the world
让他们一下子觉得不那么孤单了
and suddenly making them feel less alone.
那么  具体点说
Uh, just to talk specifics,
全球拓展到底是什么样的
what exactly would global expansion look like?
我们不感兴趣
We're not interested.
我觉得  我们该花点时间想想
I think...I think we should take a minute with this.
我想了
I have.
也许我疯了  但在我听来
Maybe I'm crazy, but it sounds to me
西方集团似乎想做我们也想做的事
like Westgroup wants the exact same things that we do.
我也还没被说服
I'm not sold yet either,
但我觉得我们该听听看
but I think we should hear this out.
我们放下过去吧
Let's leave the past where it is
一起创造点真正特别的东西
and build something truly special together.
不  当我没说
No, scratch that.
是你来创造
You build it.
这次我不会妨碍你了
I'll get out of the way this time.
你不会妨碍我吗
You'll get out of the way?
所有人  听好了
Everybody, listen up.
-卡梅伦  别这样  -事情是这样的
- Cameron, come on. - Here's what's going on.
乔·麦克米伦和西方集团能源想收购我们
Joe MacMillan and Westgroup Energy want to buy us up.
听到了吗  就是这样
You hear that? Yeah.
我们都能去市中心为石油公司大佬打工了
We can all go work for a bunch of oil company suits downtown.
这听上去如何
How's that sound to you guys?
怎么  听上去像是出卖自己吧
Oh, what, does it sound like selling out?
-没错  -因为我就是这感觉
- Yeah. - 'Cause that's what it sounds like to me.
没错  不是去设计酷炫游戏
Yeah, instead of building kick-ass games,
他们想让这里变成
they want to turn this into a place
家庭主妇能分享食谱的地方
where housewives can share their recipes.
蠢爆了
That's bullshit!
什么  等等  你不想打领带上班啊
What? Oh, wait, you don't want to wear a tie to work?
不想打卡上下班啊
You don't want to clock in and out?
-才不要  -那么你们宁可做平等的伙伴
- No. Hell, no. - So you'd rather be equal partners
一起打造你们用血汗
in a thing that you created
和泪水创造的东西
with your own blood and sweat and tears
而不是做企业食物链里没主见的小丑吗
than mindless stooges in a corporate food chain?
对
Yeah!
穆特尼  穆特尼  穆特尼
Mutiny! Mutiny! Mutiny!
-很好  -这就对了
- Great! All right. - Let's do it!
穆特尼  穆特尼  穆特尼
Mutiny! Mutiny! Mutiny!
首先我要感谢你们
All right, first off, I wanna thank you guys
在假期中抽出时间
for knocking off a few days' vacation time
一起来尝试这个点子
so we can try this thing out, all right?
我不要求你们马上全部入股
I'm not asking for full buy-in now.
我相信空谈不如实践
I believe the proof is in the pudding.
等到了时候  如果你们想入股就买入
Once those days are up, if you want in, you're in.
坦迪  EDS  通用动力和军刀
Tandy, EDS, General Dynamics, Sabre.
这么几周就要我们放弃这样的高薪吗
That's a lot of salary to walk away from after a couple of weeks.
没错  我了解
Yeah, yeah. I know it is.
所以明天我要你们每个人
And that's why tomorrow I want each of you
都把最近一张工资单带来
to bring in your most recent pay stub
我好开出对等的酬劳
so I can match 'em in good faith.
听着  我还不能马上分发停车位
Look, I'm not handing out parking spaces
和金表  因为现在只有我们  好吗
and gold watches just yet because it's just us, okay?
我说到做到  你们拿着螺丝刀和烙铁
100% fulfillment. Guys with screwdrivers and soldering irons
坐在工作台前  做最擅长的工作
sitting at these benches, doing what they do best.
等我们做起来
Once we get going,
我就在全国最大的电脑杂志上登广告
I'm dropping ads in the biggest national computer magazines.
不需要零售商店的中介
No more retail store middlemen,
不再用小隔间  不再扯淡  好吗
no more cubicles, no more bullshit, all right?
只有这些和这个
Just these and this.
呼叫乔·麦克米伦
Paging Joe MacMillan.
我们以8兆赫兹英特尔186'87系列处理器为核心
We'll standardize around the Intel 186 '87 processor
兼容配置其他硬件
running at 8 MHz.
十兆硬盘  5.25软驱
10-meg hard drive, 5 1/4 floppy.
最终要以12兆赫兹286架构处理器为核心装机
Eventually, we'll go to 12 MHz on the 286-based system,
但现在我想继续使用186架构的处理器
but for now I want to stick with the 186
好控制价格
so we can keep prices down.
你们可能想问  低到多少
How far down, you ask?
每台八百块上下
800 bucks per unit, give or take.
取决于顾客的选择
All depending on what options the customer chooses.
他们想要标准林肯城市汽车  没问题
They want a standard Lincoln Town Car, boom.
他们想要法拉利
They want a Ferrari? Hey,
他们有钱  我们就有时间
they got the money, honey, we got the time.
精巧经济的机型  只要五百块
A nimble economy job, 500 out the door.
价格比市面上所有零售品牌都要低
Prices are lower than retail brands across the board.
我们向顾客们提供无限的自主组装
We're offering the customer unlimited self-assembly
而且方便到仅需插上电源
with the convenience of plugging it in
打开开关
and flipping a switch.
这才是"开放式架构"
Open architecture, baby.
我们制造的每台机器的命运
The destiny of every box we build
都掌握在开启开关的用户手里
lays in the hands of the user turning that mother on.
你们意见如何
So, what do you say?
想一起大干一场吗
You guys want to slam one of these together or what?
这不是死刑  只是个麻烦
It's not a death sentence, it's a complication.
天晓得我们克服过不少麻烦了
And Lord knows the two of us have overcome our fair share of those.
怎么了
What?
对不起  甜心  我还在想"脑损伤"
I'm sorry, honey. I'm still on "brain damage."
只是局部  只有一些轻微影响
Microscopic. Some mild effects.
比如什么
Like what?
肌肉无力  记忆缺失
Like muscle weakness, some memory lapses.
他可能偶尔会有点不在状态
He might seem a little off once in a while.
比如半夜在你的院子里挖个坑吗
Like when he dug a hole in your yard in the middle of the night?
不不  那是工作压力导致的
No, no, that was work, stress.
多年前戈登飞来这里
What about when Gordon flew out here all those years ago
请求你父亲允许你嫁给他那次呢
to ask your father's permission to marry you?
-那是怎么回事  -妈妈  你这就无理取闹了
- What happened? - No, Mom-- now you're being ridiculous.
-那是怎么回事  唐娜  -妈妈
- What happened, Donna? - Mom.
他紧张到上错了飞机
He was so nervous that he got on the wrong plane.
结果飞到了盐湖城
Ended up in Salt Lake City.
不得不打电话找你爸爸帮他订了机票
Had to call your father, who ended up booking him a seat.
你爸还让登机口检票员确认他上对了飞机
Even told the gate agent to make sure he got on the right flight.
那不是  那挺可爱的
That's not-- that's-- it's cute.
那是
It's-- that's--
天呐  妈妈  那是我最喜欢的戈登的趣事之一
Jesus, Mom, that's one of my favorite stories about Gordon.
跟这个没关系
that has nothing to do with this.
万一病情恶化了呢
What if he gets worse?
万一他哪天坐轮椅了呢
What if one day he's in a wheelchair?
那时候怎么办
What then?
到那时我们再想办法
Well, then we will deal with it.
万一他照顾孩子的时候
What if something happens
出了什么意外呢  宝贝
when he's taking care of the girls, honey?
你考虑过这个吗
Have you thought of that?
我知道这不容易  但你得考虑啊
I know it's hard, but you have to.
或许之前
Maybe what happened--
那个孩子
the baby--
焉知非福
was a blessing in disguise.
你们什么情况了啊
Hey, how's it going over here?
就那样咯
Whatever, whatever.
你打算什么时候跟他见面
What, when are you gonna meet up with this guy?
-他叫乔治  是吧  -我也说不好
- George, right? - I don't know.
我们说要明天一起做点什么
We talked about doing something tomorrow,
但也可能不成
but maybe never.
莱夫  去吧  别怂了
Lev, do it. Stop being such a wuss.
闭嘴  你还欠我一个黑色蜘蛛侠
Shut up. You still owe me a black Spider-Man.
弄好了
I think I got it.
好啊  去看看
All right, let's go.
出价在哪
Where's how much it was for?
还没找到  你们看
I haven't found it yet, but look.
办公区翻修并扩张
Office space renovation and expansion,
-等等...  -卡梅伦拥有90%的穆特尼吗
- something-something... - Cameron owns 90% of this place?
普通创始员工
Founding entry-level employees
享有现工资64%的加薪
entitled to a 64% increase of current salary
及出售价1%的提成
and 1% of sale price.
多少的1%
1% of what?
我们已经拒绝了  所以是零蛋的1%
Well, we already said no, so it's 1% of jack shit.
先说清楚
Let's be clear.
不是你叫我来的  是别人选派我来的
You didn't bring me here. I elected to show up.
你在这间房里说的话卡梅伦都会知道
Everything you say in this room goes right back to Cameron.
而且我确信
And I have every expectation
卡梅伦知道你来见我
that Cameron knows you came to see me.
你明白这项交易很好
You know this is a good deal.
条款还算合理  但这不是我的公司
The terms are not insulting, yeah, but it ain't my company.
她对此有意见也算正常  你说是吧
Can't fault the kid for being a little squirrely, either, can you?
乔啊
Hell, Joe,
我当初还觉得你这人挺靠谱呢
you seemed like a pretty good deal to me back in the day.
我可没叫你挪用那笔钱啊  约翰
I never asked you to embezzle that money, John.
如果你不是决定自己采取行动
If you hadn't taken matters into your own hands
而是听了我的话
and instead just listened to me,
你现在就跟内森一样是百万富翁了
you'd be a multimillionaire along with Nathan right now.
你清楚这点  你是个明白人
I know you see it. You always have.
你全力支持巨人  因为你看好它
You went to bat for the Giant because you believed in it.
你加入穆特尼  因为你看好他们做的事
You're at Mutiny because you believe in what they're doing now.
去穆特尼是因为我55岁有案底  找不到工作
I'm at Mutiny because I'm a 55-year-old ex-con who can't get a job.
你可是很有价值的人才啊
You're an extremely valuable asset.
得了吧  乔
Please, Joe.
这么强的阳光照在我屁股上  我受不了
I can't take such a large amount of sunshine up my ass.
痒得慌
It makes me itch.
我们得把这个项目
We're going to need to pitch this program
推销给全球9个不同的子公司
to nine different global subsidiaries.
这很考验销售才智
That's gonna require serious sales acumen.
我们希望你加入这个团队
We want you on that team.
你们
We?
除非她奇迹般改变心意
Man, you're not pitching shit
你们什么都推销不了
unless she miraculously changes her mind,
除非她另有安排  我都会一直在她的厨房干活儿
and I work out of her kitchen until the day she says otherwise.
你是该坐角落办公室的人
You belong in a corner office.
我们这儿就有一间等着你呢
and we've got one waiting for you right here.
你在卡梅伦那边说得上话
You have Cameron's ear.
她可以随便恨我
She can hate me all she wants,
但别让她为赌气就放弃好机会
but don't let her cut off her nose to spite her face.
我知道她看重你的意见
I know you're her go-to.
不是我
It ain't me, babe.
那是唐娜吗
Is it Donna, then?
我能说什么
What can I say?
那孩子恋爱了
The kid's in love.
雅各布
Oh, Jacob.
真高兴你能来
So glad you could swing by.
约翰·博斯沃思
John Bosworth.
-久仰大名了  -过奖
- I've been hearing about you in my circles for years. - Sure.
我真的很期待
I'm really looking forward to
有你这样的资历和背景的人加入这个团队
having someone of your background and experience on this team.
相信我们都可以从彼此身上
I'm sure we both can learn a thing or two
学习到一些东西  你说呢
from each other, don't you think?
当然了  我完全同意
Oh, I think so. I think so.
-谢谢  -抱歉这么来去匆匆的
- Thank you. - Look, I'm sorry to be in and out like this.
我4点要赶去休斯顿
I have to be in Houston by 4:00,
但我听说你要来
but when I heard that you were coming in,
当然得亲自过来
I just had to come over and
-自我介绍一下  -当然  当然
- introduce myself personally. - Oh, sure, sure.
-真的很荣幸  -我也很荣幸  雅各布
- It's a real pleasure. - Pleasure's mine, Jacob, yeah.
失陪
Joe.
你知道
You know...
你在别处可找不到这么好的买卖
you're not gonna find a deal like this anywhere else.
你也许是对的
You might be right.
但我不会被你收买  乔
But I won't be bought, Joe.
如果这是卡梅伦的意愿  那我们都不会
And if that's what Cameron wants, none of us will.
但我们可以提供3.5软盘供客户选择
But we can offer an option for a micro 3 1/2.
单面还是双面
Single or double-sided?
都有  但是双面更贵
Offer both, but double costs more.
你不用整天都待在这儿
Hey, you don't have to hang out here all day, you know.
你知道这事有一阵子了  但我才刚刚知道
Look, you've been living with this for a while. I haven't.
而且不只是因为你的病
But, look, it's more than that.
我离开太久了  我想你
I've been gone too long. I've missed you.
我也想你
I've missed you, too.
-我知道这才是你去亨利家的原因  -什么
- I know that's why you went to Henry's. - What?
你需要有人陪着你  因为我没在
You needed someone else because I wasn't there for you.
你现在在了
Well, you're here now.
-戈登  -怎么了
- Hey, Gordon? - Yeah?
-马克杯放哪了  -水槽左边
- Where do you keep the mugs? - Left of the sink.
要我帮你新煮一壶咖啡吗
Want me to make you a new pot?
其实是拿去装小螺钉的
Oh, it's actually for smaller screws.
很小很小的那种
Tiny, tiny stuff.
-工作顺利吗  -好极了
- How's everything going out there? - Great.
设计原型机参数  研究改进主机
Laying out the prototype specs, digging in on mods.
戈登做得怎么样
How's Gordon handling everything?
他刚电话订购了四万美元的CPU芯片
He just bought 40 grand worth of CPU chips over the damn phone,
要我说  挺不错的
so I'd say pretty good.
-四万美元  -是啊
- $40,000? - Yeah.
你觉得这没问题吗
Does that seem okay to you?
怎么了  有问题吗
Why, is something wrong?
不不  没事
No, no, nothing.
盯着他点
Just, could you keep an eye on him
如果他看起来不对劲...
and let me know if he seems...
就告诉我
different, you know, or...
好  没问题
Sure, will do.
拉里  磨磨蹭蹭干吗呢
Larry, what's the holdup?
你在勾搭我老婆吗
You puttin' the moves on my wife?
没有
Uh, no, sir.
我们还有正事呢
We got work to do.
-你去我家了  -我以为能找到你
- You went to my house? - I thought I'd try you there.
你不在家  所以我留下了...
You weren't home, so I left the--
条款清单  你知道我那会儿在上班
The terms sheet, yeah. You knew I'd be at work.
你知道谁在我家吗
Do you know who was at my house?
我妈妈
My mother.
她以为我会因为出售
Do you know she cried when she thought
而挣这么多钱的时候都哭了
I was getting this kind of a payout from the sale?
当我不得不告诉她
And then she cried again
并不是她想的那样时  她又哭了
when I had to tell her that it wasn't true.
你懂不懂跟她那样的人
Do you-- do you understand the recklessness
撒那种谎是多么欠考虑
of telling those kinds of lies to someone like that?
我才没说谎  钱数是真的
Who's lying? These numbers are real.
给你的价格和卡梅伦
That's the same acquisition offer
还有高级员工是一样的
tendered to Cameron and the senior staff.
唯一新加的数据
The only new piece of accounting here
是你个人能挣多少钱
is what you would personally stand to make.
-就是贿赂我  -我只是替你算好了
- A bribe, you mean. - I just did the math for you.
汤姆
You know, Tom,
这些话你可以在电话上说的
you could've told me all this over the phone.
但你却亲自来了
And yet you're here.
你闯进了我家  我想回敬你
You invaded my space, I figured I'd invade yours.
你关心卡梅伦
You care about Cameron.
你是该关心她  她很特别
You should. She's special.
但你要想想  如果让她纯粹出于感情用事
But you have to ask yourself if you're doing right by her
而做出这个决定  是不是真正为她好
if you let her make this decision from a place of pure emotion.
我不会告诉她我们谈过话
I'm not even gonna tell her that we spoke.
好吧
Okay.
他只和我说了这些
That's all that he told me.
这是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
你觉得上面写的是多少钱
How much do you think it was for?
不知道
I don't know.
是五百万
It was five million.
但我们已经做出了决定
But we already made our decision,
所以回去工作  把这事忘了吧  好吗
so let's get back to work and just forget about it, okay?
不
No.
你替我们做了决定
You made our decision.
民主哪去了
What happened to democracy?
你忘了吗
Maybe your memory's failing you,
我们一起大喊着把乔赶出去了
but we all shouted Joe out of this house.
难道不是我们共同的决定吗
Didn't we all make this call?
是的  说实话我们只是好奇而已
Yeah, honestly, we were just curious, that's all.
-没关系  就这样了  -没什么
- Yeah, it's okay. Cool, so it's settled. - It's fine.
你为什么从没告诉我们你拥有90%的穆特尼
How come you never told us you own 90% of Mutiny?
你不要再想这事了
You need to let this go right now.
我们怎么还能有任何话语权
How could anything be up to us at all?
而且这事不一样吧
And shouldn't this be different?
我们不知道合同的细节
We didn't know the details of the deal
也不知道我们拒绝了五百万美元
or that we were turning our backs on $5 million.
怎么了  你想要什么
What? What do you want?
投票
A vote.
真正的投票
A real vote.
好啊
Fine.
好吧  我们投票
Yes, fine. We'll have a vote.
为了你  好让这事过去
For you, so that we can put this to bed.
大家都进来
Everyone come in here.
我点你们的名字  想卖就举手
I'll call your names. Raise your hands if you want to sell, okay?
卖
Sell.
好  知道了
Yes, got it.
阿基
Arki.
卖
Sell.
卡尔
Carl?
我能弃权吗
Can I abstain?
好吧  不卖
Okay, not sell.
神童
Wonderboy.
不卖
Not sell.
博斯沃思
Bosworth.
说啊
Well?
不卖
Not sell.
汤姆
Tom?
穆特尼
Mutiny.
汤姆
Tom?
天呐
Jesus.
卡梅伦  卡梅伦
Cameron. Cameron!
莱夫进医院了
Lev's in the hospital.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
我知道在我父亲眼中
I know my father has this idea of me
我是个受伤的小姑娘  维持不住恋情
as some damaged little girl unable to keep a relationship.
我不是很想证明他是对的
I'm not exactly eager to prove him right.
-那就别啊  -行了
- Then don't. - Oh, please,
别让我更加为难
don't make this harder than it already is.
你们聊得好热闹啊
This is a scintillating conversation.
爸爸  乔和我
Dad, uh, Joe and I--
我在达拉斯过得并不开心
well, I haven't been exactly happy in Dallas.
对我  对我们来说很不好过
It's been hard on me, on us,
上周末  我去了奥斯汀  我就想...
and last weekend I was in Austin and I was thinking that--
不不  我懂
No, no, no, no, I understand.
这里对你们来说都很陌生
Things here are new for both of you.
新工作  新家  新城市
New job, new home, new city.
是否完美呢  现在还不  但你们在打基础
Is it perfect yet? No, but you're building a foundation.
我不是那个意思
Well, that's not what I mean.
我的意思是  你一向不善于
Well, what I mean is that you were never very good
静观其变
at sitting still for anything.
你不是每次有点不舒服了
You know, you don't need to hit the reset button
就非得重新来过
every time you feel the slightest bit of discomfort.
我不是那样的
That's not what I do.
-如果你说的是彼得  -得了  莎拉
- And if you're referring to Peter-- - Oh, come on, Sara.
-你就是这样的  -好吧
- It's exactly what you do. - Okay.
我在九个国家有生意
I do business in nine different countries,
但跟你比  我简直是千年老树
but compared to you, I feel like a thousand-year-old oak tree.
你终于找到个你能信任的人
You've finally found a guy you can trust,
能帮你治愈旧伤的人
someone who can help you heal those old wounds.
老实说  我很高兴你跟乔在一起了
Frankly, I'm delighted that you're with Joe.
就现在我觉得你都更脚踏实地了
Even right now, you seem much more grounded to me.
我不希望你们俩
Look, I hate to see both of you
丢弃你们在这里构建的一切
throw away everything you've been building here
就因为你一时感到不安
just because of some anxious whimsy on your part
而且追根溯源是由于你在前夫身上犯的错
stemming from the mistakes you made with your ex-husband.
恕我直言  雅各布
With all due respect, Jacob,
我觉得你说得并不对
I don't think you know what you're talking about.
你不该这么看轻莎拉
Sara deserves a little more credit than that.
她看到人的闪光点
She sees the best in people.
这不是弱点  这是她的强项
That's not a weakness, it's her strength.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你觉得你比我还了解我女儿吗
You think you know my daughter better than I do?
我觉得我们的婚事不需要你来插手
I think we can navigate our engagement without your input.
有人想知道我是怎么想的吗
Does anybody want to know what I think?
-胜败在此一举了  -是啊
- Moment of truth. - Moment of truth.
好了
All right.
成功啦
Geronimo.
好诶
Yeah!
巨人耗了我们一年
The Giant took us a year.
专业版耗了半年
The Pro took us half a year.
而这东西我们两天就搭建好了
We got this sucker running in two days.
且不说别的  我们快多了
If nothing else, we're getting a lot faster.
我觉得我们很快都要富多了
I think pretty soon we're all gonna be a whole lot richer.
卡迪夫电子  巨人
你没事吧  戈登
You all right, Gordon?
知道吗
You know, um...
人生中最困难的事就是被击倒之后
the hardest thing in life is to get knocked down
再一次次站起来
and then get back up constantly.
但我们这么做是出于热爱
But we do it because we love it
我们内心知道  这点子是对的
and we know deep down that if it's the right idea,
可以成就比我们都伟大的事
it could be bigger than all of us.
很久以来  我不确定自己是否有这份信念
For a long time, I wondered if I was ever gonna find it.
我最接近的一次  是我的孩子
The closest I've come is my kids.
我觉得
Well...
我终于有一样东西
I think I've finally found something
能让我
that will allow me
自信地跟他们说
to say to them with confidence,
"你可以的  你可以追随梦想
"You can do it. You can follow your dreams.
不管多么艰难  你可以做到的"
No matter how hard it is, you can do it."
说得好
Hear, hear.
-干杯  -敬梦想  戈登
- Cheers... - To dreams, Gordon.
就两周前
Just two weeks ago,
我还想走进乔的办公室
I was ready to walk into Joe's office
告诉他  15磅以下的便携电脑
and tell him that a portable under 15 pounds--
是不可能做到的
it couldn't be done.
现在  巨人将是市面上最轻的电脑
And now the Giant is gonna be the lightest machine on the market.
这太值得骄傲了
And that is truly something to be proud of.
乔...麦克米伦吗
Joe as in Joe MacMillan?
什么
Uh, what?
乔怎么了
What about Joe?
总之
Um, anyways, uh...
大家做得好
great-- great work, guys.
冷静  他稳定下来了  没事的
Easy, easy. He's stable. It's fine.
他现在还不能说话
He can't talk right now.
他在睡觉  他们要他休息
He's asleep and they want him to rest.
怎么回事
What happened?
他本来约好
He was supposed to go out
今天跟网上认识的乔治约会
with George today from the network.
他们被打劫了吗
Did they get jumped?
根本没有乔治
There is no George.
就是几个男的
It was just a bunch of guys
在社区上假装是一个人
pretending to be a person on Community
好把他引出去
so that they could lure him out and...
你把用户的订阅信息给警方了吗
Did you give the police the subscriber info for the accoun
-那样应该就能...  -不  地址是假的
- that should help them-- - No, the address is phony, so...
而且这些蠢猪
of course the dumb pigs
本来也没采取什么行动
aren't even doing anything about it, especially--
我能见见他吗
Um, can I see him?
怎么
So, what?
下周再来这里吃晚饭  到时告诉他吗
Dinner here again next week? We tell him then?
刚刚在里面听你俩讲话
You know, listening to the two of you talk in there,
让我全看明白了
it all crystalized for me.
问题就在这里  你再次回到达拉斯
This is what's wrong. You're in Dallas again,
去西方集团工作  秘密搭建网络
working at Westgroup, with a network that you set up in secret--
我觉得你不告诉他
I think you didn't tell him
是因为你还不想放弃
'cause you're not ready to give up on this.
不  我们从天文馆下山的时候
No, when we came down from the observatory,
我们说过要向前看
we talked about moving forward,
但你现在的样子  你现在的趋势
but the way you're acting now, where you're headed,
你是在后退  这不是我们说好的
you're backsliding, and I didn't sign up for that.
我不知道你要我改变哪一点
I don't know what you want me to do differently.
我要你别再插手别人的公司
I want you to stop meddling in other people's companies
去建个自己的
and build your own.
像我们说好那样  去别的地方
Somewhere else, like we talked about.
-你怕什么  -我不怕任何东西
- What are you afraid of? - I'm not afraid of anything.
是你害怕你的历史和我的历史重演
You're the one who's afraid of your history, my history repeating.
不会的
It won't.
我相信自己的眼睛
I see what I see.
你本来打算投什么的
What was your vote gonna be?
她告诉你我每天放学之后
She told you how I got a cupcake and a Kayo
都有纸杯蛋糕和番茄蛋黄酱吃
every day after school.
但我妈没跟你说  那就是我的晚餐
What my mom didn't tell you was that was my dinner.
这样她用不到一美元就能喂饱我
That way, she could feed me for under a buck.
她两周前被裁员了
She was laid off two weeks ago.
但我们早说好一起吃午饭
But we already had lunch planned and
她非要穿制服  我还求她不要
she insisted on wearing her uniform and I begged her not to.
但她不希望你觉得
But she didn't want you to think...
我不希望你觉得我是为了钱
I don't want you to think that this is about money.
因为不是的
'Cause it's not.
我妈妈能撑过去
'Cause my mom will get by.
我们一向能撑过来
We always have.
这份工作对我意义非凡
This job means a lot to me.
我希望我们能一直走下去
And I hope it goes on for a long, long time.
但你对我也意义非凡
But you also mean a lot to me.
我希望我们也能
And I want us to go on
一直走下去
for a long, long time.
你给了我这份工作
You gave me this job.
这是你的公司
It's your company.
不
No.
公司是大家伙的
This company belongs to everybody.
我去打给乔
I'll call Joe.
告诉他我们愿意卖
I'll tell him we're selling.
敬今后
First of many.
第一步  扩招社区部技术人员
Step one, beef up support staff of the explosive Community functions.
第二步  为最新的游戏准备盛大发布会
Step two, prep a huge launch of the latest game,
《营救保卫战》
"Extract & Defend."
制造声势  全国电视全彩广告
Spectacular blitz. National TV spots, full-color ads.
游戏的事先缓缓
Let's hold off on the games just for a minute.
为什么
Why would we do that?
三个字CES
Three letters-- C-E-S.
消费电子产品展就在本月
The Consumer Electronics Show is this month,
据我所知
and from what I hear,
卡带主机游戏仍是大趋势
cartridge consoles still own the games business.
那雅达利呢  第一家一年损失破十亿的公司
What about Atari? First company to lose a billion dollars in a year.
任天堂
Nintendo.
他们的娱乐系统
This, uh, entertainment system thing
将在圣诞节前登陆美国
is gonna hit the States just in time for Christmas,
据说  她写的就是那个
and the skinny is that's all she wrote.
现在继续发展线上游戏
Continuing with online games at this point
只会是白浪费钱
would just be throwing good money after bad.
是啊  我们的确该小心行事
You're right. We should proceed with caution,
但游戏是大门
but games are the door.
能把用户吸引进来
They get users in.
让他们迷上网络
They get them hooked on the network.
游戏越好  门就越大
The better the games, the bigger the door.
不  社区
No. Community.
那才是门
That's the door.
依我看  也是一切
And, in my opinion, that's everything.
我们要发展那个
That's what we'll grow.
我跟他们商议的时候
A big part of my pitch to them
很重要的一项就是承诺创作自主权
was that they could maintain creative freedom.
是啊
Yeah.
高招啊
That was smart.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我...
I, um--
我去了公司
I went by the house.
他们跟我说了
They told me.
我们不知道是谁干的
We don't know who did it.
你可能永远不会知道
You probably never will.
六年级  第一天上学
Sixth grade, first day of school.
有人在我的储物柜上写了"基佬"
Someone wrote "fag" on my locker.
我去厕所拿了些纸巾
I got some paper towels from the bathroom,
弄湿  趁没人看到之前赶紧擦掉了
wet them down, and scrubbed it off before anyone could see.
第二天  他们用永久性马克笔写了20遍
Next day, they wrote it 20 times in a permanent marker.
我再也没去用我的储物柜
I never went back to my locker.
一整年都用背包背着七本教科书到处走
Carried seven textbooks in my backpack for the rest of the year.
我那时才11岁
I was only 11 years old,
就已经开始逃避了
but I was already running from something.
或许这让我的腿更有劲了
I guess it made my legs stronger,
让我的背更结实了
my back stronger.
试着真正跟人交心是很危险的
It's dangerous to try and really connect with someone.
找到一个能对其展现真我的人是很特别的
It's so special when you find a person you can be yourself with.
你曾经就是那个人
You were that.
现在是莎拉
Sara is.
别卖了
Don't sell.
他会毁了你的
He'll ruin it.
他并不是这么打算的  但他会的
He won't mean to, but he will.
他会挣大钱  让公司成为巨头
He'll make a ton of money, the company will be a juggernaut,
但你的愿景会被破坏  丢弃
but your vision will be corrupted and lost.
他会先叫停游戏开发
He'll start by pulling the plug on games.
你在干什么  乔
What-- what is this, Joe?
你之前为了让我签字那么拼命
You fight so hard to get me to sign the dotted line--
这不是我的公司
It's not my business.
我不会逼你同意的
I'm not gonna bully you into this.
这是你的公司
It's your company.
该由你来决定它的命运
You should decide what happens to it.
或许你能成功
Maybe you'll make it.
或许你不能
Maybe you won't.
但是成是败  你都能保持真我
But you'll live or die by who you really are.
那你的角色是什么
And where do you fit into all this?
没有我的份
I don't.
我要抽身离开
I'm removing myself from the equation.
戈登
Gordon?
怎么了
What is it?
出什么事了
What's wrong?
我们的第一单
Our first order.
克拉克电脑
Clark Computers.
我们正式开业了
We're officially in business.
我要去西方集团辞职
I'm putting in my notice at Westgroup.
我相信我是你爱上的那个人
I do believe I'm the person you fell in love with.
如果你要我走  我会走的
If you want me to go, I'll go.
告诉我你究竟想要什么
Just tell me what you want.
我想结婚
I want to get married.
那我们就结
That's what we'll do.
不  就今天
No, today.
两周后  我们就要搬到加州
And in two weeks, we're in California.
好
Okay.
我跟大家说清楚
Let me just make one thing clear.
这是我的公司
This is my company.
我不会卖的
And I'm not selling it.